Guide to the Records of the Leake and Watts Children's Home 1802-1983 (bulk 1831-1949) MS 377
New-York Historical Society
- Series I - Leake and Watts Orphan House in the City of New York/Leake and Watts Children's Home, Inc., 1831-1983 (bulk 1831-1949)
  - Subseries I.6 - Records of Children, Clubs, Activities and Alumni, 1843-1964
    Some additional documentation of clubs and activities may be found in Subseries I.8 - Printed Materials. Additional school material may be found in Subseries I.3 - Administrative Records (box 8).
    Noteworthy material in this subseries includes a "Punishment Book" from 1843 (Volume 169). This volume records the good and bad behavior of individual boys, and the consequences that resulted.
    - Admission Register Alphabetical (Oversize), 1843-1861 (Offsite-box LW-55, Volume 162)
    - Admission Register Chronological, 1845-1856 (Offsite-box LW-23, Volume 163)
    - Admission Register Alphabetical, 1852-1888 (Offsite-box LW-23, Volume 164)
    - Register Chronological (Oversize), 1904-1950 (Offsite-box LW-55, Volume 165)
    - Register Chronological, 1920-1949 (Offsite-box LW-26, Volume 166)
    - Register Alphabetical (Oversize), 1940-1950 (Offsite-box LW-57, Volume 167)
    - Monthly Population Changes, 1942-1944 (Offsite-box LW-24, Volume 168)
    - Monthly Population Changes, 1945-1946 (Offsite-box LW-24, Volume 168A)
    - Punishments, 1843 (Offsite-box LW-24, Volume 169)
    - Visitor's Book (including alumni and other visits), 1843-1928 (Offsite-box LW-24, Volume 170)
    - Alumni Visitor's Book, 1929-1971 (Offsite-box LW-24, Volume 171)
    - Visitors to Children, 1922-1926 (Offsite-box LW-24, Volume 172)
    - Visitors to Children, 1922-1926 (Offsite-box LW-24, Volume 173)
    - Visitors to Children, 1926-1929 (Offsite-box LW-27, Volume 174)
    - Visitors to Children, 1929-1931 (Offsite-box LW-28, Volume 175)
    - Minutes of the Leake and Watts Association (alumni), 1884-1897 (Offsite-box LW-25, Volume 176)
    - Minutes of the Leake and Watts Association (alumni), 1915-1956 (Offsite-box LW-25, Volume 177)
    - Infirmary Records, 1936-1942 (Offsite-box LW-25, Volume 178)
    - Infirmary Reports, 1938-1941 (Offsite-box LW-25, Volume 179)
    - Infirmary Records, 1940-1944 (Offsite-box LW-25, Volume 180)
    - Infirmary Records, 1942-1944 (Offsite-box LW-25, Volume 181)
    - Infirmary Records, 1942-1945 (Offsite-box LW-25, Volume 182)
    - Infirmary Records, 1945-1947 (Offsite-box LW-27, Volume 183)
    - Infirmary Records, 1945-1952 (Offsite-box LW-27, Volume 184)
    - Parish Register, 1934-1946 (Offsite-box LW-27, Volume 185)
    - Monthly Population Changes (disbound binder), 1935-1938 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 1)
    - Monthly Population Changes (disbound binder), 1939-1941 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 2)
    - Daily "Movement of Population" Records, 1937 January 1 - 1937 June 30 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 3)
    - Daily "Movement of Population" Records, 1937 July 1 - December 31 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 4)
    - Daily "Movement of Population" Records, 1938 January 1 - June 30 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 5)
    - Daily "Movement of Population" Records, 1938 July 1 - December 31 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 6)
    - Daily "Movement of Population" Records, 1939 January 1 - June 30 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 7)
    - Daily "Movement of Population" Records, 1939 July 1 - December 31 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 8)
    - Daily "Movement of Population" Records, 1940 January 1 - June 30 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 1)
    - Daily "Movement of Population" Records, 1940 July 1 - December 31 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 2)
    - Leake and Watts Association [alumni group] - Certificate of Incorporation (1886), Constitution and By-Laws (1894, 1930, 1947 and undated), 1886-1947 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 3)
    - Leake and Watts Association Correspondence, 1884-1947 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 4)
    - Leake and Watts Association - Burial Fund Correspondence and Flier, 1886-1889 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 5)
    - Booklet - Historical Account of Leake and Watts by Rev. R.M. Hayden - address delivered to, and printed by, Leake and Watts Association (2 copies), 1887 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 6)
    - Leake and Watts Association - Programs, invitations, fliers, newsletter, lyrics, clippings, 1892-1964 and undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder 7)
    - Suanca Club - Constitution and By-Laws, lists of officers and members, 1921, 1925 and undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder 8)
    - Waliro Club - Constitution and By-Laws, lists of officers and members, 1921-1925 and undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder 9)
    - Sports - schedules, lists, programs from annual sports dinners, 1939-1940 and undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder 10)
    - Dramatics - play programs, script, announcement card, 1939-1947 and undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder 11)
  - Subseries I.7 - Real Estate Records, circa 1822-1960
    The subseries includes deeds, rental agreements, and other legal documents related to real estate interests of the Leake and Watts Children's Home ca. 1822-1960 arranged chronologically and by subject in four boxes. Documents had been bound in bundles with ribbon, and are arranged in their original groups. The ribbon remains in the folders with the documents.
    These four boxes are followed by two folders (one half box) and one oversize folder containing building specifications (contractor's plans), architectural drawings and related correspondence, property surveys, and land use maps of Leake and Watts properties.
    These materials are followed by five bound volumes of Leake and Watts real estate documents, including materials of the Leake and Watts Realty Corporation and the 264-266 First Avenue Corporation.
    - Deeds and Other Documents related to Tivoli property, ca. 1822-1925 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 1)
    - Deeds and Other Documents related to Tivoli property, ca. 1822-1925 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 2)
    - Deeds, Mortgage and Other Documents related to N.Y.C. property, ca. 1889-1897 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 3)
    - Deeds, Mortgage and Other Documents related to N.Y.C. property, ca. 1889-1897 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 4)
    - Deeds, rental agreements and other documents related to Yonkers property, ca. 1834-1895 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 1)
    - 3 Deeds 1834-1873 with 1917 cover letter, 1834-1917 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 2)
    - Deeds and real estate documents bound together, ca. 1890-1905 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 3)
    - Deeds and real estate documents bound together, ca. 1890-1905 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 4)
    - Legal documents re: Yonkers and Tivoli property, ca. 1891-1960 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 1)
    - Real Estate documents bound together (1 of 2), ca. 1894-1897 (Offsite-box 21, Folder 2)
    - Real Estate documents bound together (2 of 2), ca. 1894-1897 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 1)
    - Mortgage Extension Agreements (1 of 2), ca. 1909-1922 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 2)
    - Mortgage Extension Agreements (2 of 2), ca. 1909-1922 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 3)
    - Land use maps and property surveys, ca. 1900-1960 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 1)
    - Building specifications (contrator's plans) and architectural drawings, ca. 1916-1917 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 2)
    - Land use maps, property surveys, architectural drawings and accompanying correspondence [oversize], 1891-1946 and undated (Folder OS 1)
    - Real Estate Documents, 1914-1932 (Offsite-box LW-27, Volume 186)
    - Leake and Watts Realty Corp. Stock Certificates, ca. 1935-1936 (Offsite-box LW-30, Volume 187)
    - Leake and Watts Realty Corp. Documents, 1936-1945 (Offsite-box LW-28, Volume 188)
    - 264-266 First Avenue Corp. Minutes and Corporate Documents, 1935-1958 (Offsite-box LW-28, Volume 188A)
    - 264-266 First Avenue Corp. Stock Certificates, 1935 (Offsite-box LW-30, Volume 188B)
  - Subseries I.8 - Printed Materials, circa 1843-1964
    This subseries of printed materials includes two scrapbooks of pamphlets, programs, and forms produced by Leake and Watts. The scrapbooks are followed by nine folders arranged in chronological order containing a variety of printed materials including forms, certificates, programs, reports, invitations, fundraising materials, booklets with biographical and historical sketches, newsletters, blank stationery, and ration slips.
    - Scrapbook of pamphlets, programs, clippings (Oversize), 1877-1954 (Offsite-box LW-56, Volume 188C)
    - Scrapbook of Home School/Tivoli Camp Activities and Forms, ca. 1937-1941 (Offsite-box LW-30, Volume 188D)
    - Apprentice Indenture Forms, ca. 1843-1849 and undated (Offsite-box 23, Folder 3)
    - Rules for Visitors, Conditions of Admission, Certificate upon Leaving, 1844, 1846 and undated (Offsite-box 23, Folder 4)
    - Programs of the Exercises of the Children, 1869-1893 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 5)
    - Memoir of William Henry Guest [Superintendent 1854-1876] by Frederic de Peyster [Secretary] (2 copies), 1878 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 6)
    - Reports, invitations and miscellaneous printed material, 1881 and ca. 1914-1926 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 7)
    - Fundraising pamphlets, booklets, fliers and cards, ca. 1920-1964 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 8)
    - "The Story of the Evolution of an Institution into a Home" (1931 - 2 copies) and "A Sketch of the Life and Work of John George Leake (1936), 1931, 1936 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 9)
    - Chapel and Open House programs, newsletters, invitations, blank stationery and forms, miscellaneous printed material, 1939-1950 and undated (Offsite-box 23, Folder 10)
    - Ration slips, ca. 1942-1946 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 11)
  - Subseries I.9 - Visual Materials, circa 1910-1983
    The subseries contains three boxes of photographic prints, photomechanical reproductions, and negatives, depicting activities, groups of children, and landscapes at Leake and Watts ca. 1910-1983, and some portraits of alumni or others. Most of the images of Leake and Watts were taken for publicity purposes. The photographic prints are in various sizes and formats including loose prints, prints mounted on board, and prints in bound and disbound scrapbooks. They are arranged chronologically, and also by size, photographer (when known), or format, along with the photomechanical reproductions and negatives. The subseries also includes two boxes of printing blocks used for printing images, arranged at the end of the subseries.
    - Photographic prints by A. Tennyson Beals, Jessie Tarbox Beals, ca. 1910-1930 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 1)
    - Photographic prints - miscellaneous photographers and uncredited, ca. 1910-1930 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 2)
    - Mounted photographic prints - activities, ca. 1915-1935 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 3)
    - Photographic prints by Paul Parker, ca. 1920-1935 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook booklet of photomechanical reproductions, ca. 1920-1935 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 5)
    - Photographic prints - small format, ca. 1920-1980 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 6)
    - Unbound scrapbook pages of photographic prints, ca. 1920's (Offsite-box 24, Folder 7)
    - Photographic prints, ca. 1945-1975 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 8)
    - Scrapbook of photographic prints and program of production of Rip Van Winkle, 1947 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 9)
    - Bantam 1947 - Scrapbook of photographic prints of summer activities, ca. 1947 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 1)
    - 8x10 photographic prints, ca. 1965-1983 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 2)
    - Photographic prints - portraits, undated (Offsite-box 25, Folder 3)
    - Photographic prints - portraits, undated (Offsite-box 25, Folder 4)
    - Negatives, undated (Offsite-box 25, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous photocopies of photographic prints, undated (Offsite-box 25, Folder 6)
    - Mock-up of Announcement of Gala, undated (Offsite-box 25, Folder 7)
    - Photographic prints - Oversize, ca. 1913-1960 (Offsite-box OS 1)
    - Printing Blocks, undated (Offsite-box 26)
    - Printing Blocks, undated (Offsite-box 27)
  - Subseries I.10 - Clippings, circa 1857-1980
    - Scrapbook of clippings about the Century Ball, 1932 (Offsite-box LW-28, Volume 188E)
    - Clippings, circa 1857-1914 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 8)
    - Clippings, 1930-1936 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, 1940-1980 (Offsite-box 25, Folder 10)
- Series II - Orphans' Home and Asylum of the Protestant Episcopal Church in New York, 1851-1949
  Scope and Contents
  The series consists of records of the Orphans' Home and Asylum of the Protestant Episcopal Church in New York, 1853-1949, arranged in four subseries as follows:
  Subseries II.1 - Minutes Volumes, 1851-1947
  Subseries II.2 - Records of Children, 1851-1934
  Subseries II.3 - Financial Volumes, 1852-1947
  Subseries II.4 - Other Materials, 1851-1949
  - Subseries II.1 - Minutes Volumes, 1851-1947
    The subseries contains Minutes of the Board of Trustees of the Orphans' Home and Asylum of the Protestant Episcopal Church 1851-1947, followed by Minutes of the Board's special and annual meetings 1906-1946, followed by minutes of the Ladies Committee 1853-1855, the Executive Committee 1862-1869, the Committee on Receiving and Binding Out Orphans 1853, and Minutes and Reports of the School Committee 1863-1876.
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1851-1859 (Offsite-box LW-29, Volume 189)
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1860-1862 (Offsite-box LW-29, Volume 190)
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1862-1864 (Offsite-box LW-29, Volume 191)
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1864-1867 (Offsite-box LW-29, Volume 192)
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1867-1870 (Offsite-box LW-29, Volume 193)
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1870-1875 (Offsite-box LW-29, Volume 194)
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1875-1884 (Offsite-box LW-29, Volume 195)
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1884-1890 (Offsite-box LW-29, Volume 196)
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1890-1901 (Offsite-box LW-29, Volume 197)
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1902-1911 (Offsite-box LW-29, Volume 198)
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1911-1934 (Offsite-box LW-30, Volume 199)
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1934-1941 (Offsite-box LW-30, Volume 200)
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1941-1947 (Offsite-box LW-31, Volume 201)
    - Minutes - Special and Annual Meetings of the Board of Trustees, 1906-1946 (Offsite-box LW-31, Volume 202)
    - Minutes - Annual Meetings of the Board of Trustees, 1906-1946 (Offsite-box LW-31, Volume 203)
    - Minutes of the Ladies Committee, 1853-1855 (Offsite-box LW-31, Volume 204)
    - Minutes of the Executive Committee, 1862-1865 (Offsite-box LW-31, Volume 205)
    - Minutes of the Executive Committee, 1865-1869 (Offsite-box LW-31, Volume 206)
    - Minutes of the Executive Committee, 1870-1882 (Offsite-box LW-31, Volume 207)
    - Minutes of the Executive Committee, 1883-1891 (Offsite-box LW-31, Volume 208)
    - Minutes of the Executive Committee, 1902-1904 (Offsite-box LW-32, Volume 209)
    - Minutes of the Executive Committee, 1907-1909 (Offsite-box LW-32, Volume 210)
    - Minutes of the Committee on Receiving and Binding Out Orphans, 1853 (Offsite-box LW-32, Volume 211)
    - Minutes and Reports of the School Committee, 1863-1876 (Offsite-box LW-32, Volume 212)
  - Subseries II.2 - Records of Children, 1851-1934
    The subseries contains fifteen volumes of records related to children at the Orphans' Home and Asylum of the Protestant Episcopal Church in New York, 1851-1934, arranged according to record type and then chronologically.
    - Admissions/Dismissions, 1851-1857 (Offsite-box LW-32, Volume 213)
      The subseries contains 15 bound volumes of records related to children at the Orphan's Home and Asylum of the Protestant Episcopal Church, 1851-1934.
    - Admissions/Dismissions, 1851-1866 (Offsite-box LW-32, Volume 214)
    - Register (Oversize), circa 1852-1888 (Offsite-box LW-57, Volume 215)
    - Applications, 1854-1865 (Offsite-box LW-32, Volume 216)
    - Applications, 1866-1877 (Offsite-box LW-32, Volume 217)
    - Applications, 1877-1891 (Offsite-box LW-32, Volume 218)
    - Applications, 1891-1914 (Offsite-box LW-32, Volume 219)
    - Applications, 1914-1925 (Offsite-box LW-33, Volume 220)
    - Surrrender Agreements, 1875-1888 (Offsite-box LW-33, Volume 221)
    - Surrrender Agreements, 1888-1910 (Offsite-box LW-33, Volume 222)
    - Surrrender Agreements, 1910-1934 (Offsite-box LW-33, Volume 223)
    - Visitor's Book, 1860-1879 (Offsite-box LW-34, Volume 224)
    - Visitor's Book, 1909-1910 (Offsite-box LW-34, Volume 225)
    - School Ledger and Diary, 1902-1909 (Offsite-box LW-34, Volume 226)
    - Record of Infectious Diseases, 1916-1932 (Offsite-box LW-34, Volume 227)
  - Subseries II.3 - Financial Volumes, 1852-1947
    The subseries contains 41 bound volumes of financial records of the Orphan's Home and Asylum of the Protestant Episcopal Church, arranged according to type. Financial records related to children are arranged at the end of the subseries.
    - Cash Accounts, 1852-1853 (Offsite-box LW-34, Volume 228)
    - Cash Accounts, 1854-1856 (Offsite-box LW-34, Volume 229)
    - Cash Accounts, 1856-1859 (Offsite-box LW-34, Volume 230)
    - Monthly Receipts, 1880-1891 (Offsite-box LW-34, Volume 231)
    - Monthly Receipts, 1891-1905 (Offsite-box LW-35, Volume 232)
    - Monthly Expenses, 1880-1905 (Offsite-box LW-34, Volume 233)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1858-1860 (Offsite-box LW-35, Volume 234)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1873-1880 (Offsite-box LW-35, Volume 235)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1879-1885 (Offsite-box LW-35, Volume 236)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1885-1894 (Offsite-box LW-35, Volume 237)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1895-1902 (Offsite-box LW-35, Volume 238)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1902-1907 (Offsite-box LW-36, Volume 239)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1907-1911 (Offsite-box LW-36, Volume 240)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1911-1917 (Offsite-box LW-36, Volume 241)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1917-1923 (Offsite-box LW-36, Volume 242)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1923-1928 (Offsite-box LW-36, Volume 243)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1928-1933 (Offsite-box LW-36, Volume 244)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1933-1937 (Offsite-box LW-36, Volume 245)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1937-1942 (Offsite-box LW-37, Volume 246)
    - Treasurer's Accounts, 1942-1947 (Offsite-box LW-37, Volume 247)
    - Permanent Fund, 1895-1903 (Offsite-box LW-37, Volume 248)
    - Permanent Fund, 1907-1933 (Offsite-box LW-37, Volume 249)
    - Permanent Fund, 1933-1938 (Offsite-box LW-37, Volume 250)
    - Permanent Fund, 1938-1944 (Offsite-box LW-37, Volume 251)
    - Permanent Fund, 1944-1947 (Offsite-box LW-38, Volume 252)
    - Check stubs, 1912-1913 (Offsite-box LW-38, Volume 253)
    - Check stubs, 1919-1920 (Offsite-box LW-38, Volume 254)
    - Check stubs, 1937-1938 (Offsite-box LW-38, Volume 255)
    - Children's Accounts - records of payment and accompanying correspondence, circa 1863-1894 (Offsite-box LW-38, Volume 256)
    - Payments for Children's Board, 1856-1860 (Offsite-box LW-37A, Volume 257)
    - Payments for Children's Wages and List of Children Placed Out, 1860-1881 (Offsite-box LW-37A, Volume 258)
    - Payments for Children's Board, 1876-1888 (Offsite-box LW-37A, Volume 259)
    - Payments for Children's Board, 1889-1894 (Offsite-box LW-37A, Volume 260)
    - Payments for Children's Board, 1895-1898 (Offsite-box LW-37A, Volume 261)
    - Payments for Children's Board, 1862-1875 (Offsite-box LW-38, Volume 262)
    - Payments for Children's Board, 1892-1903 (Offsite-box LW-38, Volume 263)
    - Payments for Children's Board, 1895-1905 (Offsite-box LW-39, Volume 264)
    - Payments for Children's Board, 1896-1905 (Offsite-box LW-39, Volume 265)
    - Payments for Children's Board, 1898-1903 (Offsite-box LW-39, Volume 266)
    - Payments for Children's Board, 1899-1906 (Offsite-box LW-39, Volume 267)
    - Payments for Children's Board, 1899-1907 (Offsite-box LW-39, Volume 268)
  - Subseries II.4 - Other materials 1851-1949
    The subseries contains one box of mixed materials including meeting minutes from 1851, a historical sketch by one of the managers ca. 1905, a notice of the organization's rules and regulations and menu circa 1855-1863, and correspondence and administrative materials circa 1902-1949. The subseries also includes one box of file cards regarding employees, one metal cash box, and a bible.
    - Orphans's Home Meeting Minutes (1851) and Historical Sketch (ca. 1905), 1851 and circa 1905 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 1)
    - Orphans's Home Rules and Regulations and Bill of Fare, circa 1855-1863 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 2)
    - Orphans's Home School Correspondence, Reports, Receipts, 1902-1908 and 1913 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 3)
    - List of Officers of the Orphans' Home (ring binder with interleaved materials and 1930 Constitution), circa 1930-1946 and 1947 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 4)
    - Orphans' Home Financial Correspondence, 1933 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 5)
    - Orphans' Home Employee Correspondence A-G, circa 1941-1945 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 6)
    - Orphans' Home Employee Correspondence H-O, circa 1941-1945 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 7)
    - Orphans' Home Employee Correspondence P-Z and re: other matters, circa 1942-1947 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 8)
    - Orphans' Home Withholding tax records, check stubs, misc., circa 1942-1949 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 9)
    - Orphans' Home Withholding Certificates and Employee Index Cards, circa 1944-1946 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 10)
    - Report of First Directress to Members of the Corporation (2 copies), 1947 January 9 (Offsite-box 28, Folder 11)
    - Orphans' Home Employee Index Cards, circa 1941-1945 (Offsite-box 29)
    - Orphans' Home Metal Box (Artifact), undated (Offsite-box LW-64, Object 1)
    - Bible, 1903 (Offsite-box LW-39, Volume 269)
- Series III - Society for the Aid of Friendless Women and Children / Hopewell Society of Brooklyn, 1869-1947
  The series consists of (1?) box and (how many?) volumes of materials created by the Society for the Aid of Friendless Women and Children and its successor, the Hopewell Society of Brooklyn (the same organization with a new name). Some volumes span years including both names. The materials are arranged by type, and chronologically, in four subseries as follows:
  The series consists of 2.5 boxes and 70 volumes of materials created by the Society for the Aid of Friendless Women and Children and its successor, the Hopewell Society of Brooklyn (the same organization with a new name). Some volumes span years with both names. The materials are arranged by type, and chronologically, in four subseries as follows:
  Subseries III.1 - Minutes, 1876-1947
  Subseries III.2 - Reports, 1869-1905
  Subseries III.3 - Records of Women and Children, 1869-1946
  Subseries III.4 - Financial Records, 1860-1946
  - Subseries III.1 - Minutes, 1876-1947
    The subseries contains Minutes of the Board of Managers of the Society for the Aid of Friendless Women and Children/Hopewell Society of Brooklyn 1876-1947, and Minutes of the Summerland Board of Managers 1926-1942, in bound volumes.
    - Minutes of the Board of Managers, 1876-1877 (Offsite-box LW-40, Volume 270)
    - Minutes of the Board of Managers, 1898-1899 (Offsite-box LW-40, Volume 271)
    - Minutes of the Board of Managers, 1899-1901 (Offsite-box LW-40, Volume 272)
    - Minutes of the Board of Managers, 1903-1905 (Offsite-box LW-40, Volume 273)
    - Minutes of the Board of Managers, 1905-1907 (Offsite-box LW-40, Volume 274)
    - Minutes of the Board of Managers, 1907-1910 (Offsite-box LW-40, Volume 275)
    - Minutes of the Board of Managers, 1910-1914 (Offsite-box LW-40, Volume 276)
    - Minutes of the Board of Managers, 1914-1918 (Offsite-box LW-40, Volume 277)
    - Minutes of the Board of Managers, 1918-1921 (Offsite-box LW-40, Volume 278)
    - Minutes of the Board of Managers, 1921-1926 (Offsite-box LW-41, Volume 279)
    - Minutes of the Board of Managers, 1926-1934 (Offsite-box LW-41, Volume 280)